Ruizhe Li

 ♦ Shenzhen, Guangdong Province, China
 ■ 12212830@mail.sustech.edu.cn

Biography and Research Interests

I'm now in the department of mathematics at Southern University of Science and Technology. In the first two years of my undergraduate career, I studied pure maths. What I loved most is the finite group theory. And I follow (Caiheng Li $\mbox{\ensuremath{\mathbb{Z}}}$) to study this field. But when I'm taking the convex optimization class(2024 fall), I begin to be interested in optimization gradually. Thanks to this course's teacher(Xuyang Wu $\mbox{\ensuremath{\mathbb{Z}}}$), he lead me to the asynchronous optimization field and I really love it.

Education

Southern University of Science and Technology

Sept. 2022 - Present

BS in Mathematics and Applied Mathematics

- o GPA: 3.89/4.0
- o Fields Honor class, led by the Fields Medal Winner Efim Zelmanov
- \circ Core course: Topology(A, 94), Abstract Algebra(H)(A⁺, 97), Complex Analysis(H)(A⁺, 98), Real Analysis(H)(A, 96), Numerical Analysis(A⁺, 98), Probability Theory(A⁺, 100), Ordinary Differential Equations(H)(A, 95)

Convex Analysis and application in machine learning $(A^+, 100)$

Research Experience

Convergence conditions for asynchronous optimization algorithms

Shenzhen, China Sep. 2024 - Present

Advised by Xuyang Wu

- Explore a broader scope of conditions in which many asynchronous optimization algorithms converges
- Study the convergence rate and time complexity of asynchronous optimization algorithms and find a more precise bound.

Seminars

Set theory Advised by Bochen Liu 🗹	Mar. 2023 - Jul. 2023
Fourier Analysis Advised by Bochen Liu	Sep. 2023 - Jan. 2024
Harmonic Analysis Advised by Bochen Liu	Sep. 2024 - Present

SKILLS & HONORS

${\bf Languages:} Chinese (native), English (fluent)$	
Programming Languages: Java, Python	
Scholarship: Merit Student Scholarship of SUSTech	Oct. 2023
Outstanding Student of SUSTech	Nov. 2023
Merit Student Scholarship of SUSTech	Oct. 2024
Outstanding Student of SUSTech	Oct. 2024
Competition: National Second prize in China Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling (As the captain)	Oct. 2023
First prize in China Undergraduate Mathematical Contest	Oct. 2024